# Puneeth Rao

Plano, Texas 75024 | 804-709-6993 | puneethrao21@gmail.com | SkypeID - purao5 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/puneeth-rao-567b00119/

#### Objective

Quality-driven Test Lead with ability in Web and API Automation testing in Banking, Healthcare and Telecom domains. Prepared to leverage my 9 years of IT experience in Application testing, Test Automation and Service Virtualization in Agile and DevOps Culture for SDET or QA Automation Testing role.

#### Skills

- Webservices/API Testing with **SOAPUI** and **Postman** and **RestAssured** Framework
- Web Automation using **Selenium Web driver** with **BDD Cucumber** framework.
- Performance Testing of APIs using **JMeter**
- Service virtualization experience with Wiremock and Parasoft Virtualize
- DevOps and Agile experience with CI/CD technologies Git, Jenkins and Maven

#### Certification and trainings

- AWS Certified Developer-Associate
- SDET training
- DevOps Foundation training
- SOA Testing specialization

#### **Awards**

• Round of Applause – Recognition from Wipro Testing practice for contribution throughout the year.

## **Experience**

SOA TEST LEAD | WIPRO LTD | PLANO, TX | OCT 2017 - CURRENT

| Client Name  | CapitalOne Auto Finance (COAF)   |               |
|--------------|--|---------------|
| Project Name | Auto Navigator web   | Team Size: 10 |
| Technologies | Selenium Webdriver BDD Cucumber framework for Acceptance Test Driven           |               |
|              | Development (ATDD), JMeter, SQL Developer, Postman, SOAPUI, Intellij IDE, REST |               |
|              | and SOAP concepts, Jenkins, Sauce labs, Github.                                |               |

**Description and work accomplished: Auto Navigator** by CapitalOne is a Consumer website for shopping for New and used cars from nearby dealers. The Web application makes it easy for consumers to shop for their preferred cars and also get prequalified for an Auto loan with CapitalOne and other lenders.

- Implemented **Page object model** design pattern with **BDD Cucumber** framework for regression suite which covers testing functional features of Auto Navigator Web application.
- Automated the process of Testing loan applications using JMeter Bean Shell scripting. Instead of submitting loan application from the UI which was time consuming, we automated the submission process through JMeter bean shell script and **ATDD** Selenium cucumber scripts.
- We were able to achieve faster testing cycle of whole application through regression suite execution through Jenkins before every fortnightly release, this automation gave us time to focus on sprint stories.
- Worked on recreating the performance test script for the web application to identify any code or latency issue with backend network calls made from Auto Navigator app.
- I have involved myself as an end to end QA right from smoke testing new features to DB validations for this web application along with seeing this app from product owner perspective by identifying any risk/dependencies and suggesting new ideas to the team. My product centric QA work received positive feedback from clients and colleagues.

## SOA TEST LEAD | WIPRO LTD | RICHMOND & VIENNA, VA | OCT 2015 - SEP 2017

| Client Name  | CapitalOne Bank  |               |
|--------------|--|---------------|
| Project Name | Digital eAPI and CloudTrek   | Team Size: 12 |
| Technologies | Cucumber-JVM (ATDD), RestAssured, SOAPUI, JMeter, Grafana, AWS, Splunk, Parasoft Virtualize, Wiremock, Inhouse build CICD frameworks, Eclipse IDE, REST and SOAP concepts. |               |

**Description and work accomplished:** Migrating CapitalOne's Consumer Bank APIs from Data Centers to AWS cloud platform.

- As a cloud migration team, we were able to achieve 100% migration of a critical Customer Information API and deploy it in production in east and west region of AWS.
- Led the team of QA members to move from Commercial tool like HP Service Test (UFT) to scripting in Acceptance Test driven framework. We were successful in migrated over 300 test cases to the new ATDD framework which covered tests for about 60 API-Key clients. This helped us reduce testing time and identifying test cases coverage through HTML test reports generated from framework.
- Virtualized 18 different backend calls made to the API for the performance testing phase, using these mocks we were able to do rigorous performance testing and finalize the AWS instances count and size in each region.
- Implemented Route53 for PT Stack between east and west region by using In-house built solutions, we were able to confirm resiliency of our instances through this chaos testing.
- Created Splunk dashboard and CloudWatch alarms which was very helpful during our production release.
- As we embraced Kanban, I was able to take up and complete requirement analysis, API client communications and development activities to help the team maintain the work in progress limit.

## SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER | WIPRO LTD | BANGALORE, KA INDIA | JAN 2015 – SEP 2017

| Client Name  | CapitalOne Bank   |               |
|--------------|---|---------------|
| Project Name | Real Time Messaging and Digital eAPI  | Team Size: 12 |
| Technologies | HP Service Test (UFT), HP Service Virtualization, SOAPUI, Selenium Cucumber for |               |
|              | Acceptance Test Driven Development, SQL Developer, REST, SOAP and BPEL          |               |
|              | concepts, Groovy Scripting.   |               |

**Description and work accomplished:** RTM - Digital eAPI is a middleware system of banking which is being used across various Line of business such as Commercial, Retails, Enterprise and Cards.

 Rapidly Onboarded and Tested Bank Webservices to new development framework and created Test suites for it with HP UFT framework.

## STUDENT-COMPUTER APPLICATIONS | WIPRO LTD | BANGALORE, KA INDIA | AUG 2010 - DEC 2014

| Client Name  | GlaxoSmithKline                                      |              |
|--------------|--|--------------|
| Project Name | Vaccines Direct                                      | Team Size: 5 |
| Technologies | Application Testing, HP ALM, Java J2EE and HTML, DB2 |              |

**Description and work accomplished**: North American website for Health care experts. The e-commerce website was used by licensed health care officials to order vaccines for stores, clinics and hospitals. The website catered to Clients from Canada USA and Puerto Rico.

- Responsible for white box testing of the bilingual application for UI changes of application.
- Successfully completed Security testing and validation of all input in the application after changes were made to handle vulnerabilities like XSS attacks.

| Client Name  | H <sub>3</sub> G Ericsson UK   |              |
|--------------|--|--------------|
| Project Name | IMR  | Team Size: 6 |
| Technologies | Application Testing, Intec Intermediate 5.0, Test Director, Unix Commands. |              |

**Description and work accomplished:** Business support system of the telecom client involving the technologies Intec interconnects, Intermediate 5.0 and Revenue Assurance. The support and testing were for postpaid events like calls and SMS.

 Monitoring and testing for features related to Intermediate layer of the Business Support System layer for postpaid events.

# BETA GAME TESTER | HEWLETT-PACKARD – CONTRACT | BANGALORE, KA INDIA | APRIL 2010 – JULY 2010

| Client Name  | BANDAI NAMCO                             |               |
|--------------|--|---------------|
| Project Name | PS <sub>3</sub> , PSP gaming             | Team Size: 15 |
| Devices      | PS <sub>3</sub> , X box and PSP consoles |               |

**Description and work accomplished:** The client had beta testing before the major release of PlayStation and Xbox Arcade Game Projects like Enslaved, Dark soul and Ace combat.

• Progression in the games, completing all boss levels and finishing the game.

- Regression testing and Performance testing of the game every week after defect fixes.
- Reporting UI glitches & crashes when testing the game in Ad hoc and infrastructure mode.

## Education

Birla institute of technology and science, Pilani | Bangalore, KA India | Dec 2014

MTech (Software Engineering) Degree in collaboration with Wipro academy of software excellence. A work integrated learning program. Graduated successfully with 6.77 CGPA.

**Dissertation:** Testing in SOA Environment. <a href="https://github.com/sdet21/SOAtesting?files=1">https://github.com/sdet21/SOAtesting?files=1</a>

St. Joseph's college of Arts and Science, (Autonomous) | Bangalore, KA India | April 2010

B.Sc Bachelor of Science Graduated in (Computers, Maths and Electronics) with an average of 67%